# Allie Caton

## Full-stack Web Developer

☑ alliecaton3@gmail.com 🧠 (310) 601 - 6103 alliecaton.com



github.com/alliecaton

Full-stack web developer with experience in Ruby/Rails, Javascript, and React. My experience working in technical project management gives me a deep understanding of the production process and how to develop effectively and efficiently within it. My excellent client communication and organizational skills from working as an Associate Producer with multiple clients, developers, artists, QA and stakeholders makes me adaptable and able to work well with all members of a project team.

# Projects

#### **Fruit Stand**

Demo e-commerce site for a smoothie shop with custom smoothie-builder and cart/checkout functionality.

- Developed Javascript/React/Redux frontend with a Rails/Active Record/Postgres backend.
- Robust admin dashboard allowing the "store-owner" to update orders on the frontend and backend using a user-friendly UI.
- Utilizes Redux and thunk middleware for asynchronous data retrieval and posting to the rails backend

#### music-r

SPA for finding and saving curated song recommendations.

- Communicates with and manipulates data from multiple Last.fm RESTful API endpoints to retrieve recommended song information based on user input.
- Hooks into Youtube embed API to allow users to listen to songs within the music-r application.
- Frontend utilizes vanilla Javascript, HTML, and vanilla CSS for styling.

#### Shelvd

Book tracking application with functionality for organizing books as well as a chat feature for connecting with other users.

- Frontend built using ERB within a RoR structure. Rails backend with a Postgres production database and a SQLite development database.
- Full user authentication functionality that leverages Devise and Github OAuth to make member-only features accessible/non-accessible.
- Communicates with the GoogleBooks API through the GoogleBooks gem to retrieve book data for display.

## Skills

Ruby Rails Javascript React ActiveRecord SQL/Postgresql, HTML **CSS** Heroku Git SVN

## Education

## **Flatiron School** Software Engineering Program 2020-2021

# **Boston University**

BS in Mass Communication 2014 - 2018

# Experience

#### FableVision Studios • Boston, MA

Associate Producer • 06/2019 - 10/2020

- Acted as lead project manager on 3 to 5 animation, website, game, and/or interactive projects at a time, directing the day-to-day development from pre-production to launch and beyond.
- · Managed and coordinated ongoing bug fixes, continuous optimization, and the roll-out of new features with both in-house and freelance developers, QA teams, clients, artists, and animators.
- · Demonstrated excellent client communication to uphold project vision, manage expectations, and protect project scope and budget with a wide range of client teams of up to 20 members from varied industries.

#### Production Assistant • 05/2018 - 06/2019

- · Worked closely with developers to assist with content entry into Unity, JSON, and custom-built project CMS backend structures.
- Assisted lead producers with QA, data and asset management, scheduling, and project team check-ins.